Guide to the Department of French, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- French sound archives collected by Pierre Capretz, 1959-1983; Accession 2001-A-152
  - Mauriac, F. Therese Desqueyroux, intro to film by Jean Delabroy (Box 12)
    - Therese Desqueyroux, directed by Georges Franju (Box 12)
  - Tati, J. Les Vacances de Monsieur Hulot (Box 12)
  - Guyot, A. Voyage en zig-zag, travel doc.: Avignon, Nice, ChamonoxC (Box 12)
  - Queneau, R. Zazie dans le metro, introductory talk by Henri Blanc (Box 12)
    - Zazie dans le metro, produced and directed by Louis Malle (Box 12)
  - Flaubert, G. Lecture on Flaubert by Nathalie Sarraute (Box 12)
    - Madame Bovary, lecture by Jean Boorsch (Box 12)
    - Le Sens du tragique dans Mme Bovary, lecture by R. Giraud (Box 12)
    - La Tragi-comedie de l'intellect, lecture by Victor Brombert (Box 12)
  - Fort, P. Twelve Poems (Box 12)
  - Gance, A. Abel Gance d'hier et de demain, documentary (Box 12)
  - Gide, A. Avec Andre Gide, doc on his life, with Gide's voice (Box 12)
    - Les Caves du Vatican, excerpts (Box 12)
    - L'Enfant prodigue, reading of text by M. Barnerias and Mme Pin (Box 13)
    - La Symphonie pastorale, introductory talk by Henri Peyre (Box 13)
    - La Symphonie pastorale, directed by Jean Delannoy (Box 13)
  - Giono, J. Son Oeuvre et sa Voix, biographical recollections, excerpts (Box 13)
    - Manosque, pouquoi Manosque? Giono reflects on his works (Box 13)
    - La Femme du Boulanger (Box 13)
    - La Femme du Boulanger, directed by Marcel Pagnol (Box 13)
    - Jean Giono, doc on his life with excerpts from his works (Box 13)
    - L'Accueill des etrangers a Paris (Box 13)
  - Giraudoux, J. L'Apollon de Bellac, excerpts (Box 13)
  - La Fontaine. Le Corbeau et le renard (Box 13)
  - La Bruyere. De la Flatterie (Box 13)
  - Moliere. Les Precieuses ridicules (Box 13)
  - Pascal, Racine. Le Pari de Pascal et Phedre, lecture by Lucien Goldman (Box 13)
  - Goscinny, R. Asterix le Gaulois (Box 13)
    - Asterix le Gaulois, edited (Box 13)
    - Asterix le Gausois, soundtrack only (Box 13)
    - La Grande Guerre, dramatization of the historical events of the First World War, 1914-1918 (Box 13)
  - Green, J. Christine, excerpts (Box 13)
    - Moira and Sud, excerpts with introduction by author (Box 13)
  - Guareschi, G. Le Petit monde de Don Camillo, with Fernandel (Box 13)
  - Guicharnaud, J. Quelques Maitres d'autrefois (Box 14)
  - Guitry, S. Ecotuez bien, Messieurs, a "divertissement" read by Guitry (Box 14)
    - L'Esprit de Paris, personal thoughs and reflections on life, love and literature (Box 14)
  - Brassens, G. Recital Georges Brassnes (Box 14)
    - Les Chansonniers (Box 14)
    - 1958 October 1 - December 31 (Box 14)
    - 1959 January 1 - March 15 (Box 14)
    - 1959 April 1 - September 30 (Box 14)
  - Capretz, P and T. La France a travers les ages: Prehistoire - Epoque Feodale (Box 14)
    - La France a travers les ages: Les origines de la societe moderne (Box 14)
    - La France a travers les ages: La periode de la guerre de cent ans (Box 14)
  - Re, Michel de. With author of La Revolution Francaise (rock opera) (Box 14)
  - Hoog, A. Civilisation americaine et civilisation francaise (Box 14)
  - Hugo, V. Visages de Victor Hugo, readings from his work (Box 14)
    - Six Selections read by Antoine Balpetre (Box 14)
    - Four Poems (Box 14)
    - Les Reves du jeune Hugo, an evocation of Hugo's early youth, readings from his and contemporaries' works (Box 14)
    - Pages d'exil (Box 14)
  - Ionesco, E. L'Auteur dramatique ou la tragedie du langage (Box 14)
    - La Lecon, read by Ionesco (Box 14)
    - Rhinoceros, excerpts with J. L. Barrault (Box 14)
    - Rhinoceros, author reads remarks and preface to textbook edition (Box 14)
  - Jacob, M. Leurs Debuts (Box 15)
  - La Fontaine. Le Corbeau et le renard (Box 15)
  - Lavalette, B. Optimisme, Le Cure de choc, A la Maniere de Rabelais (Box 15)
  - Armand, L. Introduction, His Life and Philosophy, comments by Armand (Box 15)
  - Beuve-Mery, H. Intro to the Man, comments by Beuve-Mery on role of newspaper (Box 15)
  - Boulez, P. Intro to Boulez and His Works, comments by Boulez about music (Box 15)
  - Lecoq, C. La Fille de Mme Angot, excerpts from comic opera (Box 15)
  - Mallarme, S. Nine Selections read by Jean Marchat (Box 15)
  - La Condition humaine, Les Voix du silence, expt read by J. Davy (Box 15)
  - Malraux, A. Excerpts read by J. Vilar, M. Bouquet, A. Malraux (Box 15)
  - Marivaux/Moliere. Les Fausses confidences, Le Misanthrope, Amphitryon, excerpts (Box 15)
  - Marivaux, P. Les Fausses confidences, Acts I/III read by Barrault and Renaud (Box 16)
    - Le Jeu de l'amour et du hasard (Compafniw Henri Doublier) (Box 16)
    - Le Jeu de l'amour et du hasard, C.F. (Box 16)
  - Marceau, F. Le Terrain d'Immacolata (Box 16)
  - Masse, P. 7000 Francais elaborent le plan (Box 16)
  - Maupassant, G. de La Parure (Box 16)
    - Un Duel, Le Bapteme (Box 16)
    - La Peur (Box 16)
    - La Ficelle (Box 16)
    - Les Bijoux (from Contes Modernes) (Box 16)
    - Le Rosier de Madame Husson, with Bourvil and Pauline Carton (Box 16)
    - Une Partie de campagne, directed by Jean Renoir (Box 16)
    - Un Mariage d'amour (Box 16)
    - Les Vieux, Un Cheval (Box 16)
  - Mauriac, F. His Works and His Voice (Box 16)
    - Ma Litterature qui s'alimente dans mon enfance (Box 16)
  - Maurois, A. L'Ecrivain et son public (Box 16)
    - La Malediction de l'or (Box 16)
  - Merimee, P. Carmen, Acts I/IV, music: Georges Bizet (Box 16)
    - Une femme et un diable, expt. (also Journal Parle, T.V.) (Box 16)
    - Tamango, read by Mainvialle and Soboda (Box 16)
  - Moliere. Les Batailles de Moliere, excerpts from works by author and some of his contemporaries (Box 17)
    - L'Avarem excerpts with Denis d'Ines (Box 17)
    - Le Bourgeois gentilhomme (Box 17)
    - Le Bourgeois gentilhomme (Box 17)
  - Truffaut, F. Tirez sure le pianiste (Box 17)
  - Moliere. Don Juan
    - mise en scene de Jean Vilar (Box 17)
    - L'Ecole des femmes (Box 17)
    - Les Femmes savantes, C.F. (Box 17)
    - La Malade imaginaire, C.F. (Box 17)
    - Le Medecin malgre lui, C.F. (Box 17)
    - Le Medecin malgre lui, T.V. Production (Box 18)
    - Le Misanthrope, excerpts, C.F. (Box 18)
    - Le Misanthrope (Box 18)
    - Les Precieuses ridicules, C.F. (Box 18)
    - Le Tartuffe, excerpts (Box 18)
    - Le Tartuffe, Acts I/V (Box 18)
    - Le Tartuffe, Acts I/V, directed by Fernand Ledoux (Box 18)
  - Montaigne, M. de. Les Essais, four selections read by George Le Roy (Box 18)
  - Montherlant, H. de.
    - Les Celibataires (Box 18)
    - Demain il fera jour (Box 18)
    - Interview avec Madeleine Renaud (Box 18)
    - Ce que j'ai voulu dire depuis 45 ans (Box 18)
    - La Reine morte, C.F. directed by Pierre Dux (Box 18)
    - Panorama de la musique concrete, I and II (Box 18)
  - Musset, A. de.
    - Alfred de Musset dramaturge, by Georges May (Box 19)
    - Les Caprices de Marianne, music by M. Jarre (Box 19)
    - Le Chandelier (Box 19)
    - Le Chandelier, poetry: Rudel, Prevert, La Fontaine and Char (Box 19)
    - Lorenzaccio, adaptation and mise en oeuvre de Gerard Philipe (Box 19)
    - Les Nostalgies d'Alfred de Musset, 13 poems (Box 19)
    - La Nuit de Mai, lu par Mme Bara de Tovar and Paul Oetly (Box 19)
    - 16 Poems read by Jean Dessailly (Box 19)
    - Poems ready by Claude Laydu (Box 19)
    - Poete maudit, by Henri Peyre (Box 19)
    - Visages de Musset: "L'Enfant du siecle lucide et desespere" (Box 19)
    - Visages de Musset: "Les Divertissements" (Box 19)
    - Visages de Musset: "Les Illuminations" (Box 19)
  - Nerval, G. de. Nerval et l'Orient, lecture by Jean Bruneau (Box 19)
    - 10 Poems read by Jacques Destoop (Box 19)
  - Nohain/Ravel. L'Heure espagnole, music: Ravel; orch: l'Opera Comique (Box 19)
  - Popp, A. Introduction a l'orchestre, narration: Francois Perier (Box 19)
  - Ortali, R. With science faculty; elections 2e tour, pt. 1, 1968 (Box 19)
    - Elections 2e tour, pt. 2; with architecture students, 1968 (Box 19)
    - Events of May '68 at Odeon; with grocer of Meudon (Box 19)
    - At Club Mediterrannee, pt. 1 (Box 19)
    - At Club Mediterrannee, pt. 2; J. Cidier on Radio-TV strike (Box 19)
  - Pagnol, P. Cesar (Box 19)
  - Pagnol, M. Marius, excerpts, beg. of Act III, with Raimu and Charpin (Box 19)
    - Le Schpountz, with Fernandel (Box 19)
    - Topaze (Box 20)
  - Lesage, A. Scenes de la vie de Gil Blas (Box 20)
  - Cocteau, J. Les Parents terribles, excerpts (Box 20)
  - Paris, J. La Jeune poesie, followed by a reading of several poems (Box 20)
  - Pascal, B. Visages de Pascal, excerpts read by P. Vaneck (Box 20)
    - Pensees (Box 20)
  - Peguy, C. Peguy et Jaures, by B. Guyon of Univ of Aix-Marseille (Box 20)
    - Poems (Box 20)
    - Monde sonore, Histoire vivante, with Bernhardt, Apollinaire, Milhaud (Box 20)
  - Pichette, H. Lecture and reading of his poetry (Box 20)
    - Les plus beaux poems de Victor Hugo a Arthur Rimbaud (Box 20)
    - Les Blasons du corps feminin (16th century) read by G. Philipe and A. Reybaz (Box 20)
    - Le Beau voyage, read by J. Chevrier, music by J. Simonot (Box 20)
  - Peguy, C. Poetry recited by George Le Roy and Reine Lorin (Box 20)
    - The Golden Treasury of French Verse, read by Jean Vilar (Box 20)
    - J. Vilar Reads Hugo, Lamartine, Merval, Apollinaire and others (Box 20)
  - Hugo and Lamartine. Poetry of Hugo and Lamartine, read by Vilar, Chevrier, Deschamps (Box 20)
  - Mallarme and Valery. Poems by Jacques Guicharnaud (Box 20)
  - Vigny; Hugo; Gautier and others. Poems of the 1st Half of the 19th Century; read by J. Chevrier, G. Philipe; P. Viala (Box 20)
    - Poemontages: small anthology of Modern French Poetry (Box 20)
    - Poems read by Madeleine Renaud (Box 20)
  - Ponge, F.
    - La Litterature poetique francaise dupuis 1940 and poems (Box 21)
    - Tresor de la poesie lyrique francaise: Middle Ages (Box 21)
    - Tresor de la poesie lyrique francaise: The Renaissance (Box 21)
    - Tresor de la poesie lyrique francaise: 17th Century (Box 21)
    - Tresor de la poesie lyrique francaise: 18th Century and Pre-romanticism (Box 21)
    - Tresor de la poesie lyrique francaise: The Great Romantics (Box 21)
  - Verlaine; Rimbaud; Mallarme. Read by James Lewis, Claude Monteux, Linette Fisher and Stephane Reilman (Box 21)
    - J. Marchat and G. May read Vigny, Musset, Larmatine, de Lisle, et al (Box 21)
    - Poetes maudits d'hier et d'sujourd'hui dit par Pierre Brasseux (Box 21)
    - Les Maudits, P. Hiegel reads: Rictus, Villon, Baudelaire, etc. (Box 21)
  - Prevert, J. Paroles, read by J. Prevert; guitar: Crolla (Box 21)
    - Promenades dans Paris, read by Muni, music: P. Delaube (Box 21)
  - Lapointe, B. Avanie et Framboise (Box 21)
    - From Ronsard to Prevert, poems and text read by Paul Viala (Box 21)
  - Apollinaire, G. Le Pont Mirabeau and Marie (1913) read by Apollinaire (Box 21)
    - Choix de poesie, read by Pierre Viala (Box 21)
  - Futurisme, Cubisme. Exposition a Paris concernant le Futurisme et le Cubisme (Box 21)
    - French Poetry of the 16th, 17th, and 18th Centuries (Box 21)
    - Lesage, Montesquieu, Nerval, La Fontaine, Potier, Goldman, Ponge, Jammes, Baudelaire, Rimbaud, Racine, Prevert, Greco, Eluard, St. Exupery (Box 21)
    - Port Royal, history of Jansenist movement and men in 17th cent (Box 21)
  - Simon, C. Roman: signification et chronologie (Box 22)
  - Michelet. Michelet, createur de l'histoire, by Georges Poulet (Box 22)
  - Prevert, J. Prevert-parle: Pourquoi? Pourquoi? (Box 22)
  - Prevost, Abbe.
    - Manon, comic opera, music: Massenet (Box 22)
    - Combray: from A la Recherche du temps perdu, introduction by P. Carpetz, read by J. Guicharnaud, 1967 April (Box 22)
    - Combray: from A la Recherche du temps perdu, introduction by P. Carpetz, read by J. Guicharnaud, 1968 April (Box 22)
    - Combray: from A la Recherche du temps perdu, introduction by P. Carpetz, read by J. Guicharnaud, 1968 November (Box 22)
    - Combray: from A la Recherche du temps perdu, introduction by P. Carpetz, read by J. Guicharnaud, 1969 March (Box 22)
    - Combray: from A la Recherche du temps perdu, introduction by P. Carpetz, read by J. Guicharnaud (narration only), 1969 March (Box 22)
    - Combray: from A la Recherche du temps perdu, introduction by P. Carpetz, read by J. Guicharnaud (music only), 1969 March (Box 22)
    - Combray: from A la Recherche du temps perdu, introduction by P. Carpetz, read by J. Guicharnaud (with EEG dissolve master), 1977 December (Box 22)
    - Proust, tel que je l'ai connu, portrait by famous friends and contemporaries (Box 22)
    - Marcel Proust: from Masterpieces to a Master's Work (Box 22)
    - Proust et la passion des images, by Jacques Borel (Box 22)
    - A Treasury of Golden Prose, read by Riquier and Le Marchand (Box 22)
  - Queneau; Michaux. Les Cocasses, two poems by each of the two poets (Box 22)
  - Queneau, R. Exercises de style, interpreted by Les Freres Jacques (Box 22)
    - Le Babillage des Carolingiens, talk on French grammar and usage (Box 22)
  - Rabelais, F. Rabelais, by Jean Paris (Box 22)
    - Selections read by Lucien Baroux (Box 22)
  - Racine, J.
    - Athalie, excerpts (Box 23)
    - Berenice, excerpts (Box 23)
    - Britannicus, excerpts (Box 23)
    - Esther (Box 23)
    - Iphigenie, excerpts (Box 23)
    - Phedre, preface, Acts I/V (Box 23)
    - Sarah Bernhardt reads, 3 texts by Racine, Zamacois, Rostland (Box 23)
    - Les Plaideurs (Box 23)
    - Radio Program from Andorre, Monte-Carlo and Luxembourg (Box 23)
    - News, U.S. current events, 1959 July 6 (Box 23)
    - Voice of America, U.S. current events, 1958 December 7 (Box 23)
    - Radio France; Radio Toulouse (Box 23)
    - Journal parle du soir (Box 23)
    - Festival E.S.S.E.C. from Paris International, 1959 March 9 (Box 23)
    - Crowds in different parts of France (Box 23)
    - Voice of America, 1958 December 28 (Box 23)
    - Voice of America, 1958 December 14 (Box 23)
    - Radio Monte-Carlo; Radio egyptienne, news, 1959 September 2 (Box 23)
    - Radio television francaise, 1958 July - September (Box 23)
    - News Algeries; Ortiz speech, 1960 January (Box 23)
    - News, 1961 July-August (Box 23)
    - News, 1961 September (Box 23)
    - News, 1961 October-November (Box 24)
    - Salade insolite (Box 24)
    - News international events, etc., 1958-1959 (Box 24)
    - News political events, etc., 1959 (Box 24)
    - Songs, Cuisinorama I; sauces (Box 24)
    - Hommage a Jacques Thibaud, from Paris International, 1959 September 1 (Box 24)
    - Radio Toulouse, Radio Alger: News, sports, 1959 July 4 (Box 24)
  - Raynaud, F. Balendar a la guerre (Box 24)
    - Rire I: three monologues (Box 24)
    - Rire II: four monologues (Box 24)
    - Three Monologues (Box 24)
    - France de nos jours, 1. Sports et plaisirs (Box 24)
    - France de nos jours, 2. Famille (Box 24)
    - France de nos jours, 3. Litterature (Box 24)
    - France de nos jours, 4. Education (Box 24)
    - France de nos jours, 5. Philosophie (Box 24)
    - France de nos jours, 6. Politique, musique et cinema (Box 24)
    - France de nos jours, 7. Theatre (Box 24)
  - Peyre, H. Renan et la Grece: Athenes ou Israel (Box 24)
  - Rictus, J. Poems read by Maurice Chevalier (Box 24)
  - Rimbaud, A. Poems read by Jean-Louis Barrault (Box 24)
    - Poems read by Sacha Pitoeff (Box 24)
    - Une Saison en enfer: "Mauvais sang" read by H. Pichette (Box 24)
    - Une Saison en enfer: "Nuits de l'enfer"; "Delires I" read by H. Pichette (Box 24)
    - Une Saison en enfer: "Delires II" read by H. Pichette (Box 24)
  - Robbe-Grillet, A. De l'Immortelle a la Maison de rendez-vous (Box 24)
    - L'Annee derniere a Marienbad, directed by Alain Resnais (Box 24)
    - L'Annee derniere a Marienbad, excerpts (Box 24)
    - Le Roman en tant que creation du monde (Box 24)
  - Romains, J. Excerpts from his works, introduction by author (Box 24)
  - Ronsard, P. Odes et Amours, poems read by Pierre Blanchar (Box 25)
    - Poems read by Jean Dessailly (Box 25)
  - Rousseau, J-J. Jean-Jacques Rousseau, documentary (Box 25)
  - St. Exupery, A. de. Son oeuvre et sa voix, introduction and excerpts (Box 25)
    - Le Petit Prince, C.F. (Box 25)
    - Le Petit Prince, C.F., excerpts (Box 25)
  - St. John Perse. Read by Jean Vilar (Box 25)
  - Sarment, J. Leurs Debuts, author tells of his life and work (Box 25)
    - Leurs Debuts, five poems recited by the author (Box 25)
  - Sartre, J-P. Les Jeux sont faits, directed by Jean Delannoy (Box 25)
    - Excerpts from his various works (Box 25)
  - Flaubert, G. Attire et repousse par Flaubert, by Jean-Paul Sartre (Box 25)
  - Sartre, J-P. Le Mur, directed by Serge Roullet (Box 25)
  - Sauguet, H. Visions infernales (Poemes de Max Jacob) (Box 25)
  - Milhaud, D. Chants populaires hebraiques (Box 25)
  - Boorsch, J. Scarron: L'Ivresse du burlesque (Box 25)
  - Scribe, E. Le Diplomate, excerpts with D. Lecourtois (Box 25)
    - Aux Temps des Dames de Chenonceaux, historical dramatization (Box 25)
  - Adamo; Four Popular Songs sung by Adamo (Box 25)
    - Twelve Songs sung by Trenet, Piaf, Cordy, Becaud (Box 25)
    - Eleven Songs; sung by Brassens, Dulac, Hardy, etc… (Box 25)
    - Military Music; Music from Lourdes Pilgrimage (Box 25)
    - Eight Songs for Children (Box 25)
    - Chants Basques et Occitans (Box 25)
  - Barbara; Eleven Songs sung by Barbara (Box 25)
  - Moreau/Bassiak; Twelve Songs sung by Jeanne Moreau (Box 25)
  - Berat, G. G. Berat Sings Twelve Greats (Box 25)
  - Brassens, G. Brassens Sings (Box 26)
    - Brassens et sa guitare (Box 26)
    - Chansons par Georges Brassens (Box 26)
    - Brassens signs "La Mauvaise reputation" (Box 26)
  - Bertin, M. Marcel Bertin: "Mon Beau Sabot dore," children's songs and poems (Box 26)
  - Montero/Brecht, Mother Courage, songs sung in French and Germaine Montero (Box 26)
  - Brel, J. Eight Songs (Box 26)
    - Eleven Songs (Box 26)
  - Montero/Bruant, Germaine Montero Sings songs of Aristide Bruant (Box 26)
    - French Canadian Christmas Songs (Box 26)
  - Champoux, P. French Canadian Folk Songs (Box 26)
  - Chevalier, M. M. Chevalier Sings four songs (Box 26)
    - A Couple Dozen Songs for Children (Box 26)
  - Vernay, L. Lee 4 Barbus, Songs for Children (Box 26)
    - A Students Choir Sings French Songs (Box 26)
    - Christmas in France, Les Petits Chanteurs de Versailles (Box 26)
    - From: Comment reussir dans les affaires sans vraiment se fatiguer (Box 26)
  - Douai, J. Recital by Jacques Douai (Box 26)
  - Dulac, J. Jacqueline Dulac Sings (Box 26)
  - Dutronc, J. Jacques Dutronc Sings (Box 26)
  - Escudero, L. Lenny Escudero Sings (Box 26)
  - Ferrat, J. Jean Ferrat Sings (Box 26)
  - Ferre, L. Leo Ferre Sings Several Popular Songs (Box 26)
  - Ferre, L. Fold Music of France (Box 26)
  - Zimirou, H. and H. French Fold Songs Sung by Henriette and Henri Zimirou (Box 26)
  - Francois, J. April in Paris, Fr. Songs sung by J. Francois; orch: M. Legrand (Box 26)
    - Mademoiselle de Paris (Box 26)
    - Vive la Francois (Box 26)
    - Mon Oncle and Le Piano de la plage sung by J. Francois (Box 27)
  - Francois, J. Popular Songs (Box 27)
  - Freres Jacques. Popular Songs (Box 27)
    - Twelve Popular Songs (Box 27)
  - Prevert, J. Ten Songs sung by Freres Jacques (Box 27)
  - Freres Jacques. Four Popular Songs (Box 27)
  - Golmann, S. Ballades et chansons de geste (Box 27)
  - Greco, J. Juliette Greco Sings, with Michel Legrand and orchestra (Box 27)
    - Saint-German-des-Pres (Box 27)
  - Guilbert, Y. Popular Songs (Box 27)
  - Hardy, F. Four Corners of the World, popular songs (Box 27)
    - Ten Popular Songs (Box 27)
    - Chansons de l'histoire de France: The French Revolution (Box 27)
  - Julien, P. Nine Popular Songs (Box 27)
    - Three Popular Songs (Box 27)
  - Leclerc, F. Felix Leclerc Sings (Box 27)
    - Modern French Songs, Children's Songs, 1900-1940 (Box 27)
    - Selection of Modern Songs by Trenet, Piaf and others (Box 27)
  - Montand, Y. Yves Montand Sings "Oldies" (Box 27)
    - Vive la rose, songs sung by Y. Montand (Box 27)
    - Songs about Paris (Box 27)
  - Van Parys, G. Germaine Montero Sings songs of Van Parys (Box 28)
  - Robert, S. Songs of Montmartre sung by S. Robert (Box 28)
  - Patachou, Bravo Patachous, Patachous sings (Box 28)
    - Patachou's Paris (Box 28)
    - French Songs Sung by Patachou (Box 28)
    - Montmarte (Box 28)
    - Le Coeur de Paris, by various singers (Box 28)
    - Chansons de poetes, lyrics of well known poets in song (Box 28)
  - Piaf, E. Edith Piaf Sings (Box 28)
    - Piaf Tonight (Box 28)
    - Piaf Sings: "Mon Legionnaire" and "LiHomme de la coloniale" (Box 28)
    - Songs sung by Chevalier, Piaf, Trenet and others (Box 28)
  - Prevert, J. Songs of Prevert sung by C. Vaucaire, E. Amado and M. Armaud (Box 28)
    - French Popular Music (Box 28)
  - Reggiani, S. Songs sung by Serge Reggiani (Box 28)
    - French Renaissance vocal music (Box 28)
    - Rounds, Fables and Songs, recited and sung by Bertin and Benoit (Box 28)
    - A La votre (Box 28)
  - Sablon, J. Songs (Box 28)
  - Sablon/Boyer, Jean Sablon and Lucienne Boyer Sing (Box 28)
  - Sheila, Songs (Box 29)
  - Stello, Stello Chante (Box 29)
  - Sylvestre, A. Songs (Box 29)
    - Television en chansons (Box 29)
  - Trenet, C. Charles Trenet Sings His Songs (Box 29)
    - My Great Successes (Box 29)
  - Tessier, Y. Tessier Sings French Troubadour Songs of the 12th and 13th Cent (Box 29)
  - Marre-Jarry, Music from Ubu Roi (Box 29)
  - Vartan, S. Songs (Box 29)
  - Vanderlove, A. Songs (Box 29)
    - Songs (Box 29)
    - Le Sport francais a 100 ans, history of sports at a school (Box 29)
    - Journal parle du soir, 1965 May 11 (Box 29)
  - Coleville, M. Mme de Stael et sa decouverte de l'Allemagne (Box 29)
  - Stendhal, L. The Letters of Stendhal (Box 29)
  - Stravinski, L'Histoire du soldat (Box 29)
  - Tardieu, J. Le Guichet, poems and excerpts from Une Voix sans personne (Box 29)
  - Bresson, R. Le Proces de Jeanne d'Arc (Box 29)
  - Prevert, J. Les Pages qu'il faut connaitre, read by Prevert and others (Box 29)
    - Conversation: Banque, Paris, 1972 (Box 29)
    - Le Beau voyage I, chansons enfantines (Box 29)
  - Camus, A. L'Etranger (Box 29)
    - L'Universite de Paris (historique) Cite U. (fonctionnement) (Box 29)
  - Freres Jacques, Le Tango interminable des perceurs de coffres-forts (Box 29)
  - Douai, J. Chansons poetiques anciennes et modernes (Box 29)
  - Brel, J. Les Grands auteurs et compositeurs interpretes (Box 29)
  - Stendhal, Le Rouge et le noir, excerpts (Box 29)
  - Dutronc, J. Dutronc Sings His Songs (Box 29)
  - Anouilh, J. Les Chansons betes (Box 30)
  - Noel, M. Marie Noel mise en chansons (Box 30)
  - Ronsard, P. de. Sonnet a Helene, read by J. Chevrier (Box 30)
  - Simenon, G. Le Chien jaune (Box 30)
    - Les Jeunes et la musique (ORTF) (Box 30)
  - Gros/De Buron, Presentation of film: Elle court…Elle court la banlieue (Box 30)
  - Corbieres, J. Festival du Marais (Box 30)
  - Monfort, S. Interview with Silvia Monfort (Box 30)
  - Berry, E. Interview with Etienne Berry (Box 30)
    - Historique de l'Occitanie, chansons en Provencal (Box 30)
    - L'Expo le Compagnonnage Vivant (Box 30)
  - Serreau/Ionesco, Interview with J.M. Serreau and E. Ionesco (Box 30)
  - May, G. Une Saison dramatique, 1955-1956 (Box 30)
  - Romains, J. Excerpts from Knock (Box 30)
  - Achard, M. Excerpts from Jean de la Lune (Box 30)
  - Beaumarchais, Le Mariage de Figaro, excerpts read by Barrault and Renaud (Box 30)
  - Musset, A. de Les Caprices de Marianne, excerpts read by Barrault and Renaud (Box 30)
    - Soleil du midi, sketch with Fernandel, Rellys and Sardon (Box 30)
  - Pierre/Thibaut 25 cm. d'humour (Box 30)
  - Tisot, H. L'Autocirculation, parody of de Gaulle; intro. By C. Varga (Box 30)